vertbaudet.co.uk 2016-03-15

# Vertbaudet Privacy Policy

## 1\. Offer Terms & Conditions 

The Vertbaudet brand is an international retail brand owned by the Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group based in France. The Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group was set up in 2013 to buy the Cyrillus and Vertbaudet brands, which were then owned by Redcats Group. Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group set up a new company, Vertbaudet UK Limited, to buy Vertbaudet's business in the UK, Channel Isles, Isle of Man and BFPO Germany (British Forces Posted Overseas) from Redcats (Brands) Limited (now known as LRUK (Retail) Limited). As part of that business purchase, Vertbaudet UK Limited acquired existing customer accounts and data relating to Vertbaudet. 

Merchandise is now offered for sale in the UK (including Northern Ireland), Channel Isles, Isle of Man and BFPO Germany by Vertbaudet UK Limited which, as is explained above, is part of the Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group. 

Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group and Vertbaudet UK Limited may look to launch new brands to expand the range of products available to customers from time to time. This information should help you to understand relevant parts of this Policy including those relating to sharing of your details within Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group, e.g. for marketing purposes. 

Where we use the words "we" or "us" in this Policy we are referring to Vertbaudet UK Limited. 

The purpose of this Policy is to explain to you how we use personal information we collect about you and includes the topics set out below:- 

  * Your confidentiality and privacy 
  * Information we might need from you 
  * How we use this information 
  * How to unsubscribe from marketing 
  * Cookies 
  * How we keep this information secure 
  * Changes to our Privacy Policy 
  * Head Office Contact Details 

If we make changes to this Policy, we will notify you by updating this statement on our website. You can access our website homepage and browse our site without disclosing your personal data. 

## 2\. Your Confidentiality & Privacy 

We guarantee to protect your privacy. We take great care to make sure you receive the best protection possible for your personal information and any financial details that you provide. The Vertbaudet website is a secure site, and any personal data we collect from you is safe from misuse. 

We abide by the Data Protection Act 1998 and we make sure that any personal information we hold is handled properly. This means that your information will be fairly and lawfully processed, that we will make sure that it is accurate, and that your information is not kept for longer than necessary. Your information will be kept secure and processed in line with your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998 and will not be transferred to countries (whether inside or outside of the European Economic Area) without ensuring that adequate protection is in place. 

As is normal for any retailer or other organisation, we use reputable businesses from time to time to supply us with a range of services such as delivery of parcels and printing of materials and it may be necessary to share your information, e.g. name/address details for parcel delivery, with those businesses. We will, of course, ensure that your information is secure and adequately protected and processed in line with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

## 3\. Information we might need from you 

Your name, date of birth, address, customer number, telephone number, e-mail address, credit/debit card number, expiry date and issue number. If you enter a prize draw or competition we will need your name, address, customer number and e-mail address. 

## 4\. How we use your Information 

####  General Information 

We may use the information you provide as follows:- 

  * To confirm receipt of your order, process it and keep you informed of progress 
  * To approve, open and run any Credit Account you may have with us and to run any Credit Account you may have with other members of La Redoute Group (including payment recovery and debtor tracing) 
  * To keep you up to date with new services, facilities, special offers and promotions (further details below) 
  * To enhance your shopping experience in the future by tailoring the site to meet your needs 
  * To administer prize draws and competitions you may enter 

####  Credit Searches 

We may also use the information you provide to perform a credit search. Before providing credit, lenders such as banks, loan companies and businesses such as Vertbaudet want to be confident that customers will repay money they lend. To help them do this, they may look at information held by organisations called credit reference agencies. The three main credit reference agencies in the UK are Callcredit, Equifax and Experian. Those agencies hold certain information about most adults in the UK. That information is called your credit reference file or credit report. The agencies get their information from lenders, from information in the public domain (e.g. electoral roll information) and from other sources. Credit reference agencies do not hold credit blacklists and do not tell a lender if it should offer credit - that is for the lender to decide. 

We may perform a credit search in the following circumstances:- 

  * If you apply for a Credit Account; 
  * When managing your existing credit facilities 

If we perform a credit search, we will search the files of credit reference agencies who record the search whether or not credit is granted. This search may also include people with whom you are "financially linked" or your "associates". You are financially linked or associated with someone if you have applied for or hold joint credit agreements or accounts with that person. The search will be seen by other lenders who use the information to make credit decisions about you. We will use this information along with credit scoring methods to assess your application and to verify your identity. To prevent or detect fraud or to assist in verifying your identity we may also make searches of the records of other companies which were formerly sister companies, e.g. La Redoute and Daxon. As part of the sale referred to in the first section of this policy, we have agreed with La Redoute Group that they will continue to manage Vertbaudet credit agreements and accounts on our behalf for a period of time. Searches may also be made by La Redoute Group on our behalf against records held by companies within La Redoute Group, e.g. if you already have a credit agreement with another brand, such as La Redoute or Daxon. 

If we enter into a credit agreement with you, we will supply details of that agreement to the credit reference agencies as well as ongoing details of your account and how you manage it. If you do not repay on time or in full we will tell the credit reference agencies who will record details of the debt. All of that information will be seen by other organisations carrying out later searches and may be used by them to make decisions about whether or not to lend to you or those individuals who are financially linked or associated with you. The information may also be used for debt tracing and the prevention of money laundering. 

We, credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies may also use the records for statistical analysis about credit, insurance and fraud. We may pass information to financial and other organisations involved in fraud prevention to protect ourselves and our customers from theft and fraud. If you give us false or inaccurate information and we suspect fraud, we will record this. 

We may use your information held within Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group, including shopping habits, to run your Credit Account if you have one. We may make periodic searches of the records of Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group and La Redoute Group companies (La Redoute and Daxon as explained above), credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies to manage your account with us, to take decisions regarding credit (including whether to make credit available or to continue or extend existing credit). Those searches will not be available to other lenders for credit assessment purposes. If you require details of the credit reference agencies from whom we obtain and with whom we record information about you please [ write to us ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") at our Head Office address below or telephone our [ Customer Care Team ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") . 

####  Marketing 

We may also use your information, including shopping habits, for marketing as set out below. If you do not wish to be contacted for marketing purposes, please see the section below headed ”How to unsubscribe from marketing”. 

  * We may contact you by mail, telephone, email or any other reasonable method in relation to products we offer for sale whether as Vertbaudet or as other brands we operate. 
  * We may contact you by mail, telephone, email or any other reasonable method to introduce products offered for sale by other Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group members and carefully selected third parties. 
  * We may share your details with other members of the Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group and those members may contact you by mail, telephone, email or any other reasonable method. 
  * We may share your details with our former sister companies, La Redoute and Daxon. 
  * We may share your details with carefully selected third parties and those organisations may contact you by mail. We will not allow such organisations to contact you by email or telephone unless you have given us express permission for us to do so. 

## 5\. How to unsubscribe from marketing 

If you decide at any time that you do not wish to be contacted for marketing purposes by Vertbaudet or you decide that you do not wish Vertbaudet to share information for marketing purposes with other brands we operate from time to time, with other members of the Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group, with La Redoute and Daxon, or with carefully selected third parties, you can unsubscribe easily by following the instructions below. 

  * ####  Marketing from Vertbaudet, our other brands or other Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group members 

Please [ write to us ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") , telephone our [ Customer Care Team ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") or [ email us ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") with your name and customer number in the message box. Please state as follows:- 

    * Name of brand from which you no longer wish to receive marketing contact (e.g. Vertbaudet) or that you no longer wish us to share information with our other brands or other Group members for marketing purposes. 
    * Type of communication you no longer wish to receive (e.g. mail, telephone, email). 

You will also have the opportunity to unsubscribe via each marketing email sent to you in accordance with the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003. 

Note: If you unsubscribe from mail from a brand, you may no longer receive a catalogue from that brand, e.g. unsubscribing from mail from Vertbaudet may mean you no longer receive a Vertbaudet catalogue. 

  * ####  Marketing from carefully selected third parties 

Please [ write to us ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") , telephone our [ Customer Care Team ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") or [ email us ](http://preview.vertbaudet.co.uk/contact.htm "contact us") with "no third party marketing" as the subject heading and your name and customer reference number in the message box. Please state as follows:- 

    * That you no longer wish us to share information with third parties for marketing purposes. 
    * Type of communication you no longer wish to receive (e.g. mail, telephone, email). 

Requests not received in the specific format indicated are in danger of being misdirected. We reserve the right for our customer representatives to contact you regarding your account where necessary. 

## 6\. Cookies 

To provide you with specially tailored information from our website and to track the effectiveness of online advertising we, in conjunction with third party companies, may use cookies. Cookies are pieces of data that a website can send to your browser and may be then stored on your system. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which web pages and any advertisements that may be placed on them and to track the effectiveness of our online advertising generally. They also help us to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website. 

This information helps us to improve the overall level of service we provide to you. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You do not have to accept cookies and can set up your web browser to automatically notify you when you receive a cookie, this will give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. Please remember that, if you disable cookies, this will affect our ability to deliver a service through our website that is more tailored to you. 

You can obtain further information about cookies from [ www.aboutcookies.org ](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) and [ www.allaboutcookies.org ](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) . Please note, however, that those sites are operated by third parties and are not owned or operated by Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group and the Cyrillus Vertbaudet Group has no control over content. 

## 7\. How we keep this information secure 

All the information above is transmitted securely using SSL encryption. This means that the information is sent in such a way that, in the extremely unlikely event that someone is somehow able to obtain this information, only we can decode the information to obtain your details. This is done by encrypting the data between your computer and our server. We encrypt the data using a certificate provided by a trusted third party, Verisign. For more details, click on the Verisign logo. 

You can tell that the data is encrypted as the address in your browser will change from http:// to https:// and a small padlock icon will appear at the bottom of your browser window. This is your guarantee that you can send your details to us with confidence. 

We are required by the Data Protection Act 1998 to follow strict security procedures in how we store and disclose information. You may be assured that we will adhere to these procedures with your personal details. 

## 8\. Changes to our privacy policy 

We keep our Policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this webpage. This Policy was last updated on June 2014. 

## 9\. Head office contact details 

Data Protection Officer 

Vertbaudet UK Limited 

2 Holdsworth Street 

Bradford 

West Yorkshire 

BD1 4AH
